

Lucas Gonçalves

Front-end Developer

I am a front-end developer with 4 years of experience, specializing in React, Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Azure, and Git. My expertise allows me to create efficient and visually appealing user interfaces, with or without a reference prototype.

+55 (11) 94202-1791

goncalves.10.lucas@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/lucas-goncalves-9b3802166/



https://github.com/lucaaspw

Academic Background

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Universidade Nove de Julho - Uninove January 2019 - December 2022 - Completed

Additional Courses

Fullstack - B7Web

August 2019 - February 2020

Front-end - Rocketseat

March 2020 - October 2020

AZ-900 - Microsoft Platform Green

November 2023 - December 2023

English Level: Intermediate

Skills

Primary

- HTML
- CSS CSS, Sass, Bootstrap and Tailwindcss
- Javascript Vanilla, React, Nextjs and Typescript
- Adobe XD, Photoshop and Figma
- Microsoft Devops and App Services
- · Git, Github, GitLab and Bitbucket

Secondary

- Javascript Vue and Angular
- · Nodejs Express
- C# Asp.Net RazorPage
- Docker
- SQL
- AWS S3, Environment Configuration, Access Policies, and Data Upload.

Professional Experience

○ SG Rentals

Aug. 2022 - Jul. 2024

Front-end Developer Pl

- Development and Improvements for B2B and B2C Websites
- Environment Configuration for Car Registration
- Development of Prototypes for New Screens Using XD and Figma
- System Integration:
 - Whitelabel System with B2B
 - Email Services (SendGrid)
- Performance Optimization:
 - CSS and JavaScript files for faster response times
- Feature Implementation:
 - Responsive landing pages (Mobile First)
 - Rate and price filters
 - Autocomplete for available airports and car rental locations

Technologies:

C#, Razor Pages, MVC, JavaScript, React, Next jQuery, HTML, CSS, Materialize, DevOps, App Services, Redis, and SQL.

UOL Editech

Apr. 2022 - Aug. 2022

Front-end Developer Jr

Development of Online Courses and Exams for Banking Institutions Objective: To test the performance of employees applying for new positions through quizzes.

Activities Performed:

- Consuming XML data for assessments
- Developing responsive landing pages (Mobile First)
- Creating interactive animations based on user actions

Technologies:

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, and Node.js.

Foster - Marketing Agency

Dec. 2019 - Apr. 2022

Front-end Jr

Development of Blogs, News Portals, and Maintenance of Websites for Hospitals (Oswaldo Cruz, HCor, and A.C.Camargo)

- Development of Custom Themes for WordPress
- Development of a Payment Platform with Angular 6
- Creation of Responsive Landing Pages (Mobile First)
- Development of Visual Assistant (VA)

WordPress, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Angular, and Node.js.